RG 005:032, Office of the Governor: John Davis Lodge (1951-1955)
Connecticut State Library
John Davis Lodge records
1951-1955
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Governor (1951-1955: Lodge)
58 cubic feet
Gov. Lodge's correspondence, subject files, and state agency files.
RG005_032
T001290
Biographical Note
Born: October 20, 1903, Washington, D.C.
College: Harvard, 1925; Harvard Law School, 1929.
Political Party: Republican.
Offices: U.S. Congress, 1947-1951; Governor of Connecticut, 1951-1955; U.S. Ambassador Spain, 1955-1961; Argentina, 1969-1974; Switzerland, 1981-1985.
Died: October 29, 1985, New York City.
The Republican's control of the governor's office in Connecticut ended with the term of John Lodge. He was the first governor to serve a four-year term, but when he left office in 1955 the Republicans would only hold it in four of the next thirty-six years. Lodge came from a long line of political leaders, including his grandfather, Henry Cabot Lodge, and his brother, Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr. Lodge received his law degree from Harvard in 1929, but spent several years as a movie actor in Europe where he made fourteen films. In World War II he was a Naval officer. Married to Francesca Braggiotti of Italy in 1929, they had two children.
Lodge entered Connecticut politics in 1947 when he was elected to the U.S. Congress. In 1950 he defeated Governor Bowles in the first election of a Connecticut governor for a four years term. Much of his time in office was impacted by the Korean War (1950-53) as the state received numerous military contracts. Lodge had legislation passed to increase benefits for the unemployed and for injured workers. Bonding was secured to help in the construction of new state facilities.
At the end of his term Lodge sought reelection, but was defeated and left office in January of 1955. He later served as U.S. Ambassador to several countries. He attempted to become a U.S. Senator in 1964, but lost to Thomas Dodd. Lodge died in 1985. His house in Westport still stands and is privately owned. The Connecticut Turnpike (Route 95) is named in his honor.
Bibliography
Congressional Quarterly's Guide to United States Elections. Washington, D.C.: Congressional Quarterly, 1994 [CSL call number GIS Ref JK 1967 .C662 1994.
Glashan, Roy R. American Governors and Gubernatorial Elections, 1775-1975. Stillwater, Minn.: Croixside Press, 1975 [CSL call number JK 2447 .G53 1975].
Janick, Herbert F. A Diverse People: Connecticut, 1914 to the Present. Chester, Conn.: Pequot Press, c1975 [CSL call number HistRef Conn Doc St22eacs v. 5].
Sobel, Robert and John Raimo. Biographical Directory of the Governors of the United States, 1789-1978. Westport, Conn.: Meckler Books, 1978 [CSL call number GIS Ref E 176 .B573].
Van Dusen, Albert E. Connecticut. New York: Random House, 1961 [CSL call number HistRef F 94 .V3].
Scope and Content
Gov. Lodge's correspondence and subject files related to state agencies, commissions, legislative bills, and appointments among other topics. Also included are state agency files.
Arrangement
Series 1. Correspondence.
Series 2. Subject Files.
Series 3. State Agency Files.
Related Material
, Hoover Institution Library and Archives, Stanford University.
, Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Index Terms
Persons:
Lodge, John Davis, 1903-1985
Subjects:
Lodge, John Davis, 1903-1985 -- Archives; Connecticut. Office of the Governor -- Archives; Connecticut -- History -- Sources; Connecticut -- Politics and government -- 1951- -- Sources; Governors -- Connecticut -- Archives
Document Types:
Records
Restrictions on Access
These records are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Container List
- Series 1. Correspondence
  - A-B (1953) (Box 533)
  - B (1954) - C (1952) (Box 534)
  - C (1953 – 1954) (Box 535)
  - C (1954) – F (1952) (Box 536)
  - F (1953) – H (1951) (Box 537)
  - H (1952) – J (1954) (Box 538)
  - K (1952) – M (1953) (Box 539)
  - M (1954) – N (1954) (Box 540)
  - N (1954) – R (1954) (Box 541)
  - S (1952) – T (1954) (Box 542)
  - U (1953) – Z (1954) (Box 543)
- Series 2. Subject Files
  - Accomplishments (Legislative and Administrative) Gov. Lodge (Box 544)
  - Adult Probation (Box 544)
  - Aging Commission Appointed by Gov. Lodge (Box 544)
  - Aging, Commission On: Folder 2, Correspondence (Box 544)
  - Aging (Committee On) Material (Box 544)
  - [Aging, Problems of] (Box 544)
  - American Prison Association (Box 544)
  - American Woolen Company: Committee Appointed by Gov. Lodge (Box 544)
  - ADA (Americans for Democratic Action) (Box 544)
  - Americans for Hungary (Box 544)
  - Anderson, Elizabeth (Box 544)
  - Annual Reports of State Agencies [Disarranged], 1951-1953 (Box 545)
  - Annual Reports ending June 1954 [Disarranged] (Box 546)
  - Appointments to Boards, Commissions, 1951 (Box 546)
  - Appointments to Boards, Commissions, 1952 (Box 546)
  - Appointments By Gov. Lodge Various Boards, Commissions, 1953; 3 folders (Box 547)
  - Appointments By Gov. Lodge to Various Boards, Commissions, 1954 (Box 547)
  - Appropriations Committee (Box 547)
  - Architectural & Engineering Fees (Box 547)
  - Arkay Building Files ([Ralph] Kolodny) [Proposed Sale of Building on Capitol Ave. to State] (Box 547)
  - Army, Dep[artmen]t, 1952 (Box 547)
  - [Atkins, Carter, Connecticut Public Expenditure Council, Gov. Lodge’s letter to, Sept. 2, 1954, re High Education Study to be made] (Box 547)
  - Atomic Energy Committee, New England Regional (Box 547)
  - Beach Erosion (Box 547)
  - Birth Control (Box 548)
  - Birth Control Internal File (Box 548)
  - Blind, Conn[ecticut] Institute of (Box 548)
  - Bohara, Michael J. [Procuring a license to practice optometry] (Box 548)
  - Bradley Field (Box 548)
  - Bridgeport Armory (Box 548)
  - Bridgeport Chamber of Commerce (Box 548)
  - Bridgeport–Stratford Tour of Governor John Lodge, 1953 December (Box 548)
  - Budget Data [From state agencies] (Box 548)
  - Budget Economy Speech, Letters Received by Gov. Lodge Re: (Box 548)
  - Budgeted Agencies, Gov. Lodge’s Letter to and Their Replies (Box 548)
  - Cancer Fund Drive (Box 548)
  - Connecticut Chamber of Commerce (George M. Williams, Pres[ident]) (Box 548)
  - Charter Oak Bridge Tolls (Box 548)
  - Chief Justice [Appointment of] (Box 548)
  - Cigar Festival, 1952 (Box 548)
  - Citizenship Committee Conference (Box 549)
  - Civil Defense: Development of Civil Defense for Colleges (Box 549)
  - Civil Rights [Commission on] [2 folders; half the box] (Box 549)
  - Clarke, Urana (Box 549)
  - Cocco, Domenick, Grand Lodge of Connecticut Order Sons of Italy in America (Box 549)
  - Columbus, Christopher [Proposed Washington, D. C. Memorial] (Box 549)
  - Commissioners, Agency Heads: Dinner at Residence Material (Box 549)
  - Committee on Foreign Affairs [Congressional Resolution to John Davis Lodge] (Box 549)
  - Condemnation: (Rights of Tenants on Property Taken) (Box 549)
  - Connecticut Committee (Box 549)
  - Connecticut Company (Fare Increase) (Box 549)
  - Connecticut Education Association (Box 549)
  - Connecticut General (New Office Building) (Box 549)
  - Connecticut Hospital Service (Box 549)
  - Connecticut River Flood Control Pact (Box 549)
  - Connecticut State Hospital Trip of Gov. Lodge – Oct. 21, 1953 (Box 550)
  - Council of State Governments [2 folders] (Box 550)
  - County Jails, Report on: (Letters to Sheriffs and County Commissioners) (Box 550)
  - Cove Island (Conn. Light and Power) (Box 550)
  - Crusade for Freedom (Box 550)
  - Danbury By–Pass (Box 550)
  - Defense Mobilization, [Federal] Office of (Charles E. Wilson [Director]) (Box 550)
  - Defense Transport Admin[istration] (James Knudson) [Administrator] (Box 550)
  - Dental Assoc[iation], Conn[ecticut] State (Dr. Ira Dow Beebe) (Box 550)
  - Dental Labs (Box 550)
  - Dispersal of Industry [Federal Security Plan] (Box 550)
  - Displaced Persons (Box 550)
  - Driver Education Award (Box 550)
  - Dual Job Material (Box 550)
  - Dunn Survey [Voting trends] (Box 550)
  - Earl, Elliot [Technical Education] (Box 550)
  - Election Laws [2 folders] (Box 550)
  - Employees Merit Awards: Hon. Charles B. Keats, [CT] Secretary of the State, Chairman (Box 550)
  - Endorsements and Statements [Disarranged] (Box 550)
  - Endorsements and Statements [Disarranged; half of the box] (Box 551)
  - Epifani, Luigi [Resident of Rome; Concern about growth of Communist Party in Italy] (Box 551)
  - Expressway Bond Committee (Box 551)
  - Fair Trade (Box 552)
  - Fairfield, Town of (Box 552)
  - Federal Power Commission 1952 (Box 552)
  - Fireworks (Box 552)
  - Flood Control & Water Policy Commission (Box 552)
  - Fore River Shipyard (Quincy, Mass[achusetts]) Re: Forrestal class aircraft carrier (Box 552)
  - (Box 552)
  - Franco–American War Veterans (Box 552)
  - Freedom Day Ceremonies (Box 552)
  - Freight Transportation on the Connecticut River, Commission, Appointed by Governor John Lodge, 1953 July 13 (Box 552)
  - Frouse Construction Co[mpany], Inc., Thomas Progue, President (Box 552)
  - Fuel Committee (Box 552)
  - Full Employment (Box 552)
  - Gambling [2 folders] (Box 552)
  - Garden and Home Food Preservation Committee (Box 552)
  - Gasoline SB 606 [CT General Assembly] (Box 552)
  - Geological & Natural History Survey (Box 552)
  - Gilbert, Roger [See “The Connecticut Committee.”] (Box 552)
  - Gill Nets, Traps and Pounds (License Fees) Lyle N. Thorpe, Sup[erintenden]t State Board of Fisheries and Game (Box 552)
  - Godfrey [Mrs.] Pensions (Box 552)
  - Governor’s Cabinet (Box 552)
  - Governor’s Office [Plans for new enclosures] (Box 552)
  - Greenwich Chamber of Commerce (Box 553)
  - Greenwich–Killingly Expressway (Box 553)
  - Gypsy Moth – Correspondence (Box 553)
  - Hamden Vocational Technical School (Box 553)
  - Harbor Commissioners (Box 553)
  - Harkness Estate (Box 553)
  - Hartford, U. S. S. (Box 554)
  - Hartford Pension Bills (Box 554)
  - Henry Whitefield House (Box 554)
  - Hill, Carlton, Re: Lewisboro, New York [Editor, New Canaan Advertiser] (Box 554)
  - Hospital Grants (Box 554)
  - Hospitality Committee (Box 554)
  - Housatonic Dyeing & Printing Co[mpany], Inc. (Mr. Gary D. Iozia, Pres[ident]) (Box 554)
  - Housatonic River (Box 554)
  - Housatonic Valley Clean Water League (Box 554)
  - Housatonic Valley Planning Association (Box 554)
  - Housing and Home Finance Agency, Raymond A. Foley, Administrator [Federal Agency] [Correspondence with Field Director John P. Kane] (Box 554)
  - H. R. 5892 (A Bill to increase the amount of Federal Aid to State and Territorial Homes for the support of disabled soldiers, sailors, and airmen of the United States) (Box 554)
  - Hungarian Material [Re: Soviet Incursion into Hungary] (Box 554)
  - Hurricane [Result in Massachusetts] (Box 554)
  - Hypertrichology, Senate Bill 48 (Box 554)
  - I Am An American Day (Box 554)
  - Indian Material [Schathticoke Claims] (Box 554)
  - Institutional Building Program Commission (Box 554)
  - Intergovernmental Cooperation (Box 554)
  - Intergovernmental Relations, Committee on, Washington, D. C. (Box 554)
  - Iron Curtain Refugee Campaign, Carl Spaatz, Chairman (Box 555)
  - Italian Medical Schools (Box 555)
  - Izaak Walton League of America (Box 555)
  - Jewish Holiday Voting (Box 555)
  - Job Reclassification [State jobs; 2 folders] Includes Report: “Reclassification and Salary Plan State of Connecticut” (New York: Barrington Associates, Inc., March 31, 195 (Box 555)
  - John, Sarah F. (Box 555)
  - Judges [2 folders] (Box 555)
  - Judges, Local (Box 555)
  - Juvenile Delinquents (Box 555)
  - Korea (Box 555)
  - Korean Relief Campaign: Connecticut Committee (Box 556)
  - Korean Veterans’ Committee (Box 556)
  - Laurel Club (Box 556)
  - League of Women Voters of Conn[ecticut], Inc. (Box 556)
  - League of Women Voters: Gov. Lodge – Abe Ribicoff (Box 556)
  - Lee, Richard, Mayor of New Haven (Box 556)
  - Legislative Leaders 1953 General Assembly (Box 556)
  - Leipner, Benjamin ([State] Senator) (Box 556)
  - Libraries [In Massachusetts] (Box 556)
  - Lojzim, Mr. & Mrs. William (Sally) (Box 556)
  - MacArthur, Douglas [General] [Governor’s Invitation to speak before Connecticut General Assembly and reply declining] (Box 556)
  - Manufacturers Assoc[iation], 2 folders (Box 556)
  - Maltbie, Judge [William] (Box 556)
  - McWilliams, John D., Mrs. (Norwich, Connecticut) (Box 556)
  - Medical and Dental School (Box 556)
  - Memberships (Box 557)
  - Memorandums, 1954 (Box 557)
  - Mental Health (Box 557)
  - Mental Health Authorities, Northeast Conference State – Myrs, Robert C. (Dr.) (Box 557)
  - Mental Health Conference, Detroit, 1954 February 8-9 (Box 557)
  - Mental Health, De[partmen]t of (Box 557)
  - Mental Health Program of Conn[ecticut] (Gov.’s Informal Committee Report) (Box 557)
  - Mental Hospitals, Relief of (Box 557)
  - Metropolitan District (Box 557)
  - Middletown State Welfare Depart[ment] Removal from Middletown to Meriden (Box 557)
  - Milk Pasteurization Letters (Box 557)
  - Minimum Wage [Law] (Box 558)
  - Mississippi, Removal of Connecticut Industry to (Box 558)
  - Monday Meeting (Box 558)
  - Moody–Dingell Bill (Box 558)
  - Morency, Paul W. (First Day Stamp Issue) (Box 558)
  - Morse, Harry F. (Conn[ecticut] Circle) (Box 558)
  - Mount Riga Property (Box 558)
  - Murphy, Francis S. (Hartford Times) (Box 558)
  - Murtaugh, Hon. John M. Chief City Magistrate, New York (Box 558)
  - Narcotics (Box 558)
  - National Guard (Box 558)
  - National Production Authority (Manny Fleischmann) (Box 558)
  - Natural Gas: Algonquin & Northeastern (Box 558)
  - Natureopathic B[oar]d (Box 558)
  - New Britain Hospital (Box 558)
  - New England Council (Box 558)
  - New England N. Y. Interagency Committee (Box 558)
  - New York Herald Tribune, N[orth] E[ast] Section (Box 558)
  - Northeastern Gas Transmission Company Correspondence (Box 558)
  - Northeastern Gas Transmission Material (Box 558)
  - Norwalk Lock Company (Box 558)
  - O’Brien, Edmund W. (Personal) (Box 558)
  - O'Donnell Assoc[iates] Gen[eral] Ag[en]t Aetna Life Insurance Company Re: Group life Insurance – State of Conn[ecticut] Policy No. 1474R (Box 558)
  - Off–the–Job–Sickness and Disability Insurance Bill (Gov.’s Committee) (Box 558)
  - Office Bills (Box 558)
  - Office of Price Stabilization (Box 558)
  - Oil Imports H. R. 5895 (Box 559)
  - Oil Imports Correspondence (Box 559)
  - Paradise Playground (Box 559)
  - Pardons, Board of: Dockets for December 6, 1954 Meeting (Box 559)
  - Pardons and Parole: “Abel” to “Curtis” (Box 559)
  - Pardons and Parole: “Davis” to “Dwyer” (Box 559)
  - Pardons and Parole: “Erway” to “Loraine” (Box 559)
  - Pardons and Parole: “Macchio” to “Zowine” (Box 559)
  - Pardons and Parole (Box 559)
  - Pen Stabling Code (Gov. Dewey of New York State) (Box 559)
  - Phoenix Insurance Co[mpany] Building (Box 559)
  - Physically Handicapped Week Correspondence (Box 559)
  - Physicians’ Residences (Box 559)
  - Physiotherapy Technicians, Conn[ecticut] State Board of Examiners for (Box 559)
  - Pinella's Fair – Remarks (Box 559)
  - Pipelines and Natural Gas, 3 folders (Box 559)
  - Poetry Day Statement Corresp[ondence] (Gov. John Lodge) (Box 560)
  - Poland Material (Governor’s Statement to the Polish American Congress, Chicopee, Massachusetts, In Connection with “Justice for Poland” Radio Broadcast) (Box 560)
  - Portrait (Gov. Lodge) (Box 560)
  - Powdrell and Alexander Factory, Danielson, Conn[ecticut] (Box 560)
  - Powered Flight (50th Anniversary), Connecticut Committee (Box 560)
  - Program Budgeting (Performance Budget) (Box 560)
  - Property Owners Assoc[iation] of Connecticut (Mrs. Amy Kotseroplos, President) (Box 560)
  - Public Schools, State program for assistance to communities for the building and operation of (Gov. Lodge’s directive to Herb[ert] MacDonald) (Box 560)
  - Public School B[ui]ld[in]g Commission (Box 560)
  - Red Cross (Box 560)
  - Re–Districting State Senate (Box 560)
  - Refugee Relief Act: Gov. Lodge’s Conn[ecticut] Committee (Box 560)
  - Rehabilitation Material (Box 561)
  - Rehousing Committee Appointed by Governor Lodge (Box 561)
  - Rent Control [5 folders; half the box] (Box 561)
  - Reorganization Material [Of State Government] (Box 561)
  - Republican National Committee Material (Box 561)
  - Republican National Convention (Box 561)
  - Republican State Central Committee, 2 folders (Box 561)
  - Resignations, Recommendations, Congratulations, Letters of Introduction (Box 562)
  - Resources for the Future, Mid – Century Conference on; Norvell W. Page, Conference Director (Box 562)
  - Retirement Material (Box 562)
  - Rivers and Harbors Congress; Washington, D. C., 1954 May 25-26 (Box 562)
  - (Rockland Project New Britain Teachers’ College), Conn. V–6237 (Box 562)
  - St. Lawrence Seaway (Box 562)
  - Sardinia: Dr. Ge[orge] Mofino (Box 562)
  - School Children, Transportation of, Re: Reimbursement to Towns for (Box 562)
  - Schlossback, B. M. [Dispute re: admission to the bar] (Box 562)
  - Seely – Brown, Horace [Connecticut member of U. S. House] (Box 562)
  - Shelton Arms Apartments, Bridgeport (Box 562)
  - Sloate Chevrolet Company, Inc. (Box 562)
  - Small Business Administration (Box 562)
  - Small Business Committee (Box 562)
  - Smith, Francis C. (Box 563)
  - Smith, Grady Lee (Extradition Letters) (Box 563)
  - Special Session [General Assembly] (Box 563)
  - Sportsmen’s Clubs, Connecticut State League of (Box 563)
  - Stamford Lighthouse (Box 563)
  - Standardization Committee (Box 563)
  - State and Municipal Bonds (Tax on Certain of These Bonds) (Box 563)
  - State and Sub–divisions, Committee Appointed By Gov. Lodge (Box 563)
  - State Bar Assoc[iation] of Conn[ecticut] (Meade Alcorn, Jr.] [Re: Probate Court Referendum] (Box 563)
  - State Owned Cars, Auto Regulations (Box 563)
  - Steamship Terminal, Commissioners of (State Pier) (Box 563)
  - Steel Governors (Box 563)
  - Steel Mill [Possible Construction in Connecticut], 3 folders (Box 563)
  - Stratford Toll Station (Box 563)
  - Subversives, Statutes [of]: Attorneys General Council of State Gov[ernmen]ts [one third of box] (Box 564)
  - Suggestion Systems (Box 564)
  - Suggestion Systems for State Employees, 1952 (Box 564)
  - Supreme Court of Errors (Conn[ecticut]) [Correspondence with Chief Justice Allyn L. Brown] (Box 564)
  - Surplus Property (Donable Surplus Property Program) (Box 564)
  - Taft, Robert A. (Connecticut Committee) (Robert A. Hall) (Box 564)
  - Tax Claims, Compromise (Box 564)
  - Teachers’ Colleges (Box 564)
  - Teachers’ Retirement Assessments SSB 754 (Box 564)
  - Teachers’ Retirement Fund (Box 564)
  - Television Educational Correspondence (Box 564)
  - Television, Educational Use of Channels (Box 564)
  - Television, Educational (Box 565)
  - Television Series – Gov. Lodge (Box 565)
  - Textile Committee, [The New England] (Box 565)
  - Textile Committee (Permanent) (Box 565)
  - Textile Industry (Re: Movement to the South) (Box 565)
  - Tidelands (Submerged Lands) (Box 565)
  - Toll Collectors (Box 565)
  - Toll Collectors: Irregularities in Connection with Toll Collections (Box 565)
  - Tolland County Tour By Gov. Lodge (Box 565)
  - Torrington Vocational Technical School (Box 565)
  - Training Schools and Juvenile Agencies, Nation[al] Assoc[iation] of (Box 565)
  - Treasury Dept. U. S. Savings Bond Div[ision] (Box 565)
  - Treasury, Secretary of (John W. Snyder) (Box 565)
  - Tuberculosis Sanatoria: (Transfer of Patients from Mental Hospitals to Tuberculosis Sanatoria) (Box 565)
  - Turner, J. L. [Suffield man held in jail in Springfield, MA] (Box 565)
  - Unemployment Compensation (Box 566)
  - United Nations Defense Fund, Inc. [Governor Lodge, Honorary Chair, Connecticut Committee] (Box 566)
  - United Nations Day Committee Connecticut Chairman for 1954 – Dr. James Halsey of the University of Bridgeport (Box 566)
  - United Service Organizations U. S. O. (Box 566)
  - United World Gov[ernmen]t (Box 566)
  - Valley Forge, Pennsylvania (Box 566)
  - Vergnano, Joseph, [Opposition to Virginia Extradition Warrant For] (Box 566)
  - Veterans, 1952 (Box 566)
  - Veterans’ Pamphlet (Box 566)
  - Veterinary School (Box 566)
  - Washington Crossing Park Ceremonies (Box 566)
  - Washington Pilgrimage, 1954 May 1-2 (Box 566)
  - Watertown Charter Bill (Box 566)
  - Waugh Report [Final Report, January 3, 1951, Humane & Welfare Institutions Building Program Commission, Albert E. Waugh, Chair] (Box 566)
  - Weight Distance Tax (Box 567)
  - White House Conference on Highway Safety, 1954 February 17-19 (Box 567)
  - Willimantic, Town of, Public Health Survey (Box 567)
  - Wooden Church Crusade, Inc. (Fulton Lewis, Jr. [National Chair]) [Churches for West Germany] (Box 567)
  - Workmen’s Compensation Commission (Box 567)
  - World Veterans Fund, Inc. (Box 567)
  - Wright Acres Housing Development [Investigation of] (Box 567)
  - Yale Corporation (Box 567)
  - Young American Medals Committee (Box 567)
  - Zoning Law Material (Box 567)
- Series 3. State Agency Files, 1951-1955
  - Adjutant General, 4 folders (Box 568)
  - Aeronautics Dep[artmen]t (Box 568)
  - Agricultural Experiment Station (Box 568)
  - Agriculture, Dep[artmen]t of, Comm[issione]r John Christensen (Box 568)
  - Alcoholism Commission (Box 568)
  - American School for the Deaf, 3 folders (Box 568)
  - Architectural Examining Board (Box 568)
  - Athletic Commission Francis D. Cerlanek [Commissioner] (Box 568)
  - Attorney General, 2 folders (Box 568)
  - Auditor (Box 568)
  - Banking Department, 1951 (Box 568)
  - Banking Dep[artmen]t, 1952 (Box 568)
  - Barbers, Board of Examiners [Civil Rights in Public Accommodations] (Box 568)
  - Blind, State Board of, Education of [Executive Secretary] (Box 569)
  - Budget (Robert Weir [Director]) (Box 569)
  - Cedarcrest Sanatorium, 1952 (Box 569)
  - Children and Youth, Commission on (Box 569)
  - Child Study & Treatment Home, Conn[ecticut], 2 folders (Box 569)
  - Chronically Ill, Aged & Infirm (Box 569)
  - Chronically Ill, Aged and Infirm, Comm[ission] on the Care and Treatment of (Box 569)
  - Civil Defense, 5 folders (Box 570)
  - Civil Defense Advisory Council (Box 570)
  - Civil Defense (Committee set up by Gov. Lodge), 1953 October 22 (Box 570)
  - Civil Defense Meeting Called By Gov. Lodge, 1953 November 23 (Box 570)
  - Comptroller (Box 570)
  - Conn[ecticut] Reformatory (Box 570)
  - Connecticut Safety Commission, 4 folders, half the box (Box 570)
  - Conn[ecticut] Safety Commission, 2 folders (Box 571)
  - Conn[ecticut] School for Boys (Box 571)
  - Conn[ecticut] State Farm for Women (Niantic) (Box 571)
  - Conn[ecticut] State Hospital [Middletown] (Box 571)
  - Connecticut State Library, 2 folders (Box 571)
  - Conn[ecticut] St[ate] Medical Examining Board (Box 571)
  - Development Commission [Connecticut], 3 folders (Box 571)
  - Education, 3 folders (Box 572)
  - Education, Conference on: (State and White House Conferences) (Box 572)
  - Education, Dep[artmen]t of (Box 572)
  - Education, Dep[artmen]t of, 1952 (Box 572)
  - Education, Governor’s Fact Finding Commission on (Box 572)
  - Fairfield State Hospital (Box 573)
  - Farms and Markets (Box 573)
  - Finance and Control, 6 folders; more than half box (Box 573)
  - Fisheries and Game (Box 574)
  - Fisheries and Game Dep[artmen]t, 2 folders (Box 574)
  - Food and Drug Commission, 2 folders (Box 574)
  - Geological and Natural History Survey, Connecticut (Box 574)
  - Healing Arts, State Board of (Box 574)
  - Health Department, 2 folders (Box 574)
  - Highway Department: The files of this agency are disarranged. Summaries of these boxes appear in the next three citations. (Box 574)
  - Highway Department (Box 575)
  - Highway Material (Comm[issione]r G. Albert Hill), 3 folders (Box 575)
  - Highway Department (Box 575)
  - Highway Correspondence, 1951 (Box 575)